Inventory of the Administrative Management Society Archives, 1941-1987
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Administrative Management Society Archives, 1941-1987
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 226
4 linear feet
Administrative Management Society
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the Department by Clyde T. Jeffrey in September and November of 1986.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Richmond Chapter of the National Office Management Association was organized in 1940 with 31 Charter members. Coinciding with a change in the name of the National (International) organization, the name of the Chapter was changed on January 1, 1964 to the Richmond Chapter of the Administrative Management Society.
The objectives of the Richmond Chapter are: 1. To promote a free exchange of ideas in office organization, operation and management. 2. To promote efficiency and economy in office administration by encouraging the application of scientific methods and standardization. 3. To assist educational institutions in interpreting the needs of commerce and industry relating to suitable training for a business career. 4. To hold meetings from time to time to consider and discuss subjects of mutual interest in the general field of administrative management. 5. To encourage the professionalization of the Chapter in the Society's program for certification of administrative managers.
Scope and Content Information
The Administrative Management Society files consist of Public Information and NOMA scrapbooks (1960-1969), early miscellaneous information (1941-1970) and the President's files (1981-1987).
Arrangement
Arrangement
Materials arranged alphabetically and chronologically therein
Organization
The papers of the Administrative Management Society are arranged in 3 series. Series I--Early Miscellaneous Files (1941-1970), Series II--President's Files (1981-1987), Series III--Public Information Albums and NOMA Scrapbook (1960-1969). The scrapbooks are stored with other scrapbooks in the old stack area. The series are arranged alphabetically and then chronologically. Papers within each folder proceed chronologically from back to front of folder.
Contents List
- Early Miscellaneous Files 1941-1970
  - Anniversary Celebration--20th 1960 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report--President 1949 (Box 1)
  - Area Report 1958 (Box 1)
  - Chapter Services 1965-1968 (Box 1)
  - Charter Information 1941 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws 1961 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Reports 1970 (Box 1)
  - Membership Notices 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Minutes 1946 (Box 1)
  - Minutes 1946-1960 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters 1965 (Box 1)
  - NOMA Fellowship Award 1960 (Box 1)
  - Papers and Speeches 1956 (Box 1)
  - President's Annual Report 1953 (Box 1)
  - Salary Surveys 1959 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports 1957 (Box 1)
  - Yearbooks 1969-1970 (Box 1)
- President's Files 1981-1987
  - AMS Conference Day 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Services 1981-1986 (Box 2)
  - Advisory 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Agendas 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Area IV 1985 (Box 2)
  - Attendance and Social 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Budgets, Financial Reports, Treasurer's Operations--1st folder 1985 (Box 2)
  - Budgets, Financial Reports, Treasurer's Operations--2nd folder 1985 (Box 2)
  - Budgets, Financial Reports, Treasurer's Operations--1st folder 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Budgets, Financial Reports, Treasurer's Operations--2nd folder 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Chapter Achievement Program 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Chapter Goals 1981-1985, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Chapter Services 1983-1986 (Box 2)
  - Committee of 500 1983, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Constitution and By-Laws 1982, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence--1st folder 1985 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence--2nd folder 1985 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence--3rd folder 1985 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Education 1981, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Financial Management 1984-1987 (Box 2)
  - First Vice President 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Human Resources 1984-1987 (Box 2)
  - International AMS 1986 (Box 2)
  - Leadership Reports--1st folder 1985 (Box 2)
  - Leadership Reports--2nd folder 1985 (Box 2)
  - Leadership Reports 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Management and Data Processing Salaries Report 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Management Education 1984-1986 (Box 3)
  - Membership-1st folder 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Membership--2nd folder 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Membership 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Membership Retention 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Membership Survey 1981, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Merit Awards 1983, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Minutes, Secretary's Operations--1st folder 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Minutes, Secretary's Operations--2nd folder 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Minutes, Secretary's Operations--3rd folder 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Minutes 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Newsletters 1984 (Box 3)
  - Newsletters 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Office Automation 1984-1987 (Box 3)
  - Officer's Meetings 1985 (Box 3)
  - Public Information 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - President's Annual Report 1985 (Box 3)
  - President's Annual Report 1986 (Box 3)
  - Recommendation of Membership Goals for CAP 1985 (Box 3)
  - Second Vice President 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Significant Dates 1984, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Third Vice President 1985-1986 (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks
  Scrapbooks are housed in their own area and have their own numbering system.
  - Richmond Chapter Administrative Management Society 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Richmond Chapter Administrative Management Society 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - National Office Management Association 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Management Society, Public Information Album 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Management Society, Public Information Album 1966 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Management Society, Public Information Album 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - National Office Management Association 1958-1959 (Box 4)